Guide to the Peter J. Gay Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Correspondence, 1960-2015; Series III
  - Penguin-Schnitzler, 2007-12-13 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Postcards, 1982-2003 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Quack, Sibylle, 2006-05-27-2006-05-29 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Recommendations, 2004-2006 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Reichert, 1994-1995 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Sales Tax, 2003 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Talk at Athens, 2006 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Universiteit Utrecht, 1994-1995 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Unknown manuscript on the 19th Century, 1980-1990 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Why Romanticism Matters, 2012-2013 (Box 22, Folder 11)
- Photographs and slides, 1891-2015; Series IV
  Series IV is arranged alphabetically.
  Series IV comprises photographs, slides, and negatives that are mainly personal in nature. Subjects of the photographs include Gay, his family, buildings and monuments from various vacations, and professional events and activities. Also available in this series are the photographs with arrangement notes that he used for My German Question. For drafts and other materials related to My German Question, see Series II, Writings.
  - General, Circa 1990 - Circa 2015 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Amsterdam Prize for History, 1990-1991 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Cape Sounio, Greece, 2007 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - England, 1955 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Events
    - General, 2004-2006 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Time Life People of the Century, German press, Yale University, and New York Public Library events, 1999-2000 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Family photographs, 1912-2006 (Box 23, Folder 7-13)
  - France, 1955 (Box 23, Folder 14, Box 24, Folder 1-2)
  - Gay, Peter, Circa 1950 - Circa 2003 (Box 24, Folder 3-6)
  - Honeymoon, 1959 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Housebuilding, 1978 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Institute of World Affairs scrapbook volume I, 1945 (Box 25)
  - Institute of World Affairs scrapbook volume II, 1945 (Box 26)
  - Italy, 1955 (Box 24, Folder 9-10)
  - Japan, 1945 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Manderscheid, Undated (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - My German Question, 1891-1946; 1998 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Negatives, 1949-1978 (Box 24, Folder 14-15)
  - New York Public Library Cullman Center, Circa 1999 - Circa 2003 (Box 27, Folder 1-2)
  - Pagoda - Vermont, 1960s? (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Professional associations, 2000-2008 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Professional events, 2005 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Spain, 2000 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Venice, Italy, 1955 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Vermont, 1979 April (Box 27, Folder 8)
- Personal papers, 1950-2008; Series V
  Series V comprises personal papers, records, and mementos. Materials include notebooks and diaries; reviews of Gay's works; interviews with Gay; administrative documents from professional organizations such as phone directories and minutes; and financial and property records. There is also ephemera from events and trips Gay made.
  Series V is arranged alphabetically.
  - General, 2002-2007 (Box 28, Folder 1-3)
    Materials in this folder were received from the donor in the same folder without any unifying title. They include unidentified photographs, insurance records, clippings, and correspondence.
  - Address book, Circa 1999 - Circa 2003 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - American Academy and Institute of Arts and Letters, membership roster, 1991 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - American Psychoanalytic Association, Committee on History and Archives, 1983-1986 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Apartment lease, 2006 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Appearances by Peter Gay, 1976; 1989-1993 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Architectural drawings of Peter Gay's apartment, 2002-03-28 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Articles
    - General, 1950 - Circa 2006 (Box 28, Folder 10-11)
    - Peter Gay, 1978-2009 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Book reviews, 1987-2000 (Box 29, Folder 1-2)
  - Book World interview with Peter Gay, 1991-06 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Brazilian press clippings, 1997-1999 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Contracts, 1997-2006 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Cullman Center for Scholars and Writers Fellows directory, 1999-2003 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Diabetes information, 1995-2002 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Dorchester Abbey history, Undated (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - End notes on Rehfeld text on Peter Gay, Circa 1983 - Circa 1990 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Estate planning, 2005 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Freud's death, Circa 1995; 1 (Box 37)
  - German language book reviews, 1996-1998 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Induction of Harry C. Payne as President of Williams College, 1990 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Interview with Peter Gay, Circa 1999 - Circa 2002 (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Letter to the editor of the Jewish Daily Forward, 1992-03-06 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Manhattan diaries, 2006-2007 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Medical records, 1984-1999 (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Mementos, 1965-1967; 1993-1994 (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - Modern Language Association Chicago meeting, 1990 (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities grant proposal RO-21851, 1954-1993 (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - Notebooks
    - General, Circa 1969 - Circa 1975 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Modernity, Circa 1969 - Circa 1975 (Box 30, Folder 2-3)
    - Psychonalysis, 1976 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - The Science of Memory, 1969-1971 (Box 30, Folder 5-6, Box 31, Folder 1-2)
  - PEN America event invitation, 1968 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Peter Gay, 1989-01-10; 1 (Box 38)
  - Peter Gay interview, 1989-10-21; 1 (Box 39)
  - Poster for talk at the Whitney Humanities Center, Circa 1970 - Circa 1993 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Post war in Germany and Poland reflections, Roma Ben-Atar, 1999-11-14; 1 (Box 40)
  - Program from performance of Ariadne auf Naxos, Circa 2003 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Records related to Ruth Gay's death, 2006 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Reviews, 1958-1962 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Reviews of Peter Gay's work, 1997-2003 (Box 31, Folder 8-9)
  - Reviews of Modernism, 2007-2008 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Reviews of Schnitzer's Century, 2002-2003 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Solicitations for contributions for a statue, Undated (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Swales, Peter, 2006-09-28 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - "Two Centuries of France," TOTAL Information, 1989 (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Unidentified tape, 1 (Box 42)
  - WNYC Radio- Peter Gay, Circa 1990-circa 2015; 1 (Box 41)